We made it. We made it.
All right, you guys.
>> Got Dave tonight. Good to see you guys.
>> Uh, all right. So, sorry, we just uh
just uh finished up the seventh round.
Obviously, you see the guys are upstairs
kind of finishing up um the undrafted
process, kind of grinding through that.
Um you know, we'll add a few guys there.
Not going to be a huge class of
undrafted guys, but we'll have a few of
those guys that we hopefully get locked
up here in the next half hour or so. Um
you know, day started um took Caleb
Proctor out of um defensive tackle out
of Southeast Louisiana. Um you know,
kind of uh came on through the process.
Had a really good season this year.
really productive season. Um saw him
down at the East West game and then
continued his strong spring process.
Worked out well um both at the combine
and his proday and then we had him in
here on a 30 visit. Enjoyed our time
with him there. Um and then Reggie
Virgil um you know had a good year this
year at Texas Tech. Had a good season.
Um another guy that we had enjoy big
personality on Reggie entertaining guy.
had him in here on a 30 visit as well.
Um, sixround uh Carson Sherar um
linebacker out of University of Iowa.
Sorry, I got a little allergy thing
going on here. Um, you know, productive
player for Iowa this year. Had been a
productive special teams player his
whole career. Um, you know, excited what
he can do for us defensively in the
kicking game and then finished up at the
top of the seventh round with uh Jaden
Williams, um, offensive tackle from from
Miss. So, um, no movement, no trades.
Um, you know, had a couple
opportunities. Nothing quite got us
excited to to move out on anything.
That's the way it goes sometimes, but,
um, you know, excited about the the
seven guys we added at the in the
undrafted group. We'll see how that all
shakes out. But, um, you know, I think
we added some some guys that are going
to help out our our team and, um,
increase the competition throughout all
levels of the team. So, let it, uh,
we'll let you guys fire him at us. Dave,
with uh with with a guy like Caleb, um
how do you kind of go about measuring
what he can be compared to maybe some of
the opposition he might have played at?
I mean, you're watching the game tape,
but there's there's got to be some
projection, right?
>> Yeah. I mean, the the good thing is he
played against LSU this year. Obviously,
that's the tape that everybody's going
to go to, but he did play against other
schools in the past, you know, um FBS
school, stuff like that. and then you
have him in an all-star game. So, you
get to watch him for multiple practices
against the bigger school comp. Uh it's
a case where the kid succeeded in each
one of those opportunities and he's also
been able to stack weight. Uh I think at
his proday he was up into the 290s, you
know, so still tested very well. So,
you're seeing some growth potential as
well as being able to compete when you
put them on the same level some of those
bigger school guys. It seemed like uh as
you guys went through the day, you guys
ended up with a lot of players in this
draft class that uh were high on that
athleticism scale. Is that something you
guys were looking at or is that just
coincidence?
>> I'd say more coincidence, but you know,
obviously um like more athletic the
better. Um yeah, I've seen that I've
seen that used, you know. Um you know,
uh yeah, our guys tested high. That's
that's good. That's good. I wouldn't say
it's it's something that we necessarily
target. Although, you know, whenever we
can add a good athlete, that's always a
positive.
>> Are there certain positions where you
see that as maybe more valuable than
others to to have some of that elite
level athleticism?
>> Uh, sure. I mean, I think in every
position whenever, you know, but I I I
also think you got to be you be careful.
Um, you know, there's guys that that
test really well and score well on that
and then maybe they put the pads on and
they get on the field and that may not
always translate. So, you know, that's
that's one metric. Um, you know, I would
say there there's plenty plenty of
examples of guys that that um test pot
test highly on that type of stuff and
then that doesn't translate to the field
and the opposite. There's guys that
don't test well, but hey, when you turn
on the tape, you're wow, this guy's a
pretty good athlete. So, it's it's
another piece.
>> One of those examples of the last thing
you were talking about, Reggie was
saying, you were actually happy that he
ran the 45740
might slip down the board. What did he
show you on tape? because he's talking
about how he can take the top off
defenses. You don't think that when you
see four, five, seven. What did he show
you on tape that kind of made you feel
like he has that skill set?
>> Yeah, I think that's a great example. I
mean, you know, when you when you watch
the tape of of Reggie, he's played
against high level of competition this
season at Texas Tech and, you know, they
played made it into the playoffs and and
played against good teams. I mean, you
don't turn on the tape and and say
Reggie's slow, you know? So, um, in the
end, that's what matters. Like there can
be guys that run really fast and test
really fast and then they don't show
that on tape and you know Reggie when
you turn on the tape of Reggie he he
does not play slow. So that's that's
more important is what's on tape.
>> With Kobe I I saw him listed anywhere
between just right under 6'2 to 6'3.
How will his height translate to the NFL
kind of impact what he can do here?
>> Well I mean it's really that's where
he's going to have to improve his
technique take the coaching. Um you know
you always hear low man wins and
leverage and stuff like that. So, if you
have loose hips, if you can sink and
bend your knees and your ankles, which
Caleb can do, it could be an advantage
to you. But, you have to have your hand
placement correct. You have to have
enough lower body strength, all those
kind of things, uh, it's not like
shorter is necessarily better. But, um,
he's not to the point where he's so
height deficient that he can't play a
certain position or in a scheme, you
know what I mean? And especially rushing
the passer, when you have bigger
offensive linemen who might be a little
stiffer trying to get down on you and
you could sink and get around, uh, that
can be an asset, you know what I mean? M
you uh obviously the draft board didn't
necessarily fall to get a an edge type
player. Um kind of where do you see the
pass rush edge group for you right now
as the roster stands?
>> Yeah, I mean I think we got we got a lot
of guys there that played a lot of ball
between uh you know Sweaty um Baron
Xavan um you know BJ uh BJ had a you
know tough year last year coming off the
knee and you know never really looked
quite you know all the way back. Um you
know Jordan Burch going into his second
year you So I I think we have a group
and then also Elliot Brown Neku in that
in that room as well. So you know I
think we have a group that is it's a
good mix of guys that have are
experienced that played a lot. Um you
know and we got to find a way to put
them in the best position. So um
obviously always going to look to add
and and increase and and raise the uh
talent level. Um but it just didn't work
out that way to add to that group and uh
over the last three days.
>> A lot of guys are coming from winning
programs. How much stock do you put into
that when you're doing the evaluation?
Um, I mean it's nice, but I, you know, I
don't, I don't know that that's
necessarily a focal point, you know,
but, um, obviously you like guys that
have been around winning. You like guys
that, you know, they're they're
obviously coming from programs that are
doing something right. So, that's always
good, always good to see guys, and then
that's going to help them make that
transition um, to a higher level of
competition. So, not necessarily a focal
point, but it's also a nice benefit.
>> Monte, with Jaden, I know he played both
sides of the line. Is there a plan to
start him out on one side or just kind
of use that versatility to start off?
>> Yeah, I mean he's he's played played u
you know mainly right tackle but also
saw quite a few snaps at left tackle as
well in his career. I mean I think
something 34 or something starts in his
career. So um you know another guy that
um you know he's played against good
competition in the SEC. Um but also he's
probably blocked as good of guys in
practice like with the defensive line
that they had coming out of there last
year. Um he's he's saw good competition
throughout his whole career. So, um, you
know, with the with that with the tackle
position, it's it's one that we work all
our guys, both sides, and that'll be no
different for Jaden.
>> Just going off that, you bring back
Elijah Wilkinson. Is that someone you
see right now as a starting right
tackle, just given what you guys did in
the draft and other moves?
>> Um, yeah, I mean, Elijah, you know,
Elijah started 16 games or something
last year for Atlanta. So, yeah, I think
he'll certainly be in the mix. um you
know, not really naming starters
anywhere right now, but I think Elijah
will definitely have a have a chance
there. Um Elijah's another guy who he's
played a lot of ball. He's played at
different positions. He started, you
know, the first go around with us, he
was inside at guard. Um he's also played
a lot of tackle in his career, so like
the versatility that he has, but yeah,
he'll definitely be in the mix at right
tackle.
>> Day always seems to be a little more
like volatile in terms of like the the
player talent and the dart post and
stuff, but you guys have found talent
pretty much all three prior drafts on
day three. Is there a common denominator
you find with all of these like round
guys to have them see the success they
have in the NFL?
>> Um, no. I just think, you know, we have
a pretty good process. We put a lot of
work into it. Him and I, Rob Kissle,
spend a lot of hours up there watching
the tape of later round guys. Um, I
don't think that's universal through
everybody's draft process where um, the
top level decision makers pour into the
late rounds as much as they do the early
rounds. Um, we got a lot of good scouts
who who have conviction on some of these
guys. We have an analytics department
who helps guide us. You know, they got
their systems, all their different
charts, their Bellstar system, whatever
they use. But so we get a lot of input
from a lot of people and we take it
seriously. You know, um, as a lifetime
scout, I hate when people like, ah, it's
just a six or seven, who cares? Like,
really? I can name you a lot of good
players who were found in those rounds
who end up mattering for their team. So,
I think as long as you emphasize it, you
know, you should be able to do it pretty
well.
>> Sorry. We talked to Monty yesterday
about Carson playing in some high
pressure games and moments. You have a
number of guys who played in the playoff
and then even Caleb's game at LSU was
high pressure. You know, how do you as a
scout kind of evaluate or where do you
put playing in big games, big moments on
your list of I guess intangibles and
whatnot?
>> Well, I think it's important, you know,
clutch play, you you could label it
that, but it's more so, you know, you're
looking for matchups, too. Who's the guy
playing against? it could be a big game
and he's got a weak opponent and he goes
off in that game. But, um, you know,
it's really the matchups of, you know,
Carson Becks going against Texas A&M's
defense or, you know, Ohio State's
defense, things like that, um, that
you're looking at as much as what is the
stage, you know what I mean?
>> Along those lines, um, I think you guys
drafted three or four guys that played
in the Shrine Bowl particularly and you
had mentioned earlier about Proctor. you
get to see them against those guys. Like
the ability to see those guys in those
all-star games against guys that are
going in the draft and maybe are a
little bit higher than even if they
played in a big conference because those
are the best of the best. I mean, how
important are those games? And do you
guys take a good chunk of what you're
getting out when you go to these these
all-star games?
>> Yeah, I mean, I think any exposure you
get is important. The thing about
all-star games is you get or your scouts
get to go to these games and watch the
guys consecutive practices in a row,
which you don't really do at schools.
You you might hit a school in August,
hit it again in October, hit it again
maybe late November or something, but
they're watching guys practice. Boom,
boom, boom. Uh, so they get a feel for
like the competition. Some guys will
improve over the course of this, you
know, hey, this guy's improving. If he
can do that, there's more there. And the
other thing is like we have our coaches
at these games. Chris Cook worked the
East West Shrine game. He knows Jaden
from that game. So, he can tell us,
"Hey, the guy was really good in the
meeting room." He learned here, here's
this technique that he picked up pretty
quickly. I was teaching more, you know,
vice versa. If it's negative impact,
something like that. Clearly, it wasn't
in that case, but uh so that is um very
valuable to us. But it's not necessarily
any more important than any other one,
but you you get a a good experience when
you dial in on that stuff. Dave, with
Carson Shy, he was talking about how
much pride he takes in playing special
teams, but in what ways can you see his
linebacker instincts when you play
special teams,
>> run hit, I mean, that's the name of the
game. Like, you don't see the guy
putting the brakes on before he runs
through somebody's face. And that's what
special teams is, you know what I mean?
So, uh, linebacker obviously is a
position where everybody leans on that
position for special teams play. And
when a guy has that background, like
usually know the guy's tough, you
usually know he'll work hard, whether he
can run or not, like all things that
translate to defense eventually. You
know,
>> you said your undrafted class won't be
very big. Why? What goes into that
decision?
>> Just really roster number. You know, our
roster was at a point where um we didn't
have a ton of room. So, you know, it's
it really comes down to that. I think
we'll be six to eight somewhere in
there.
>> How do you say you approach the draft?
You're very big on like best player
available, but do you go into a draft
thinking, hey, I want to accomplish
this. I want to maybe like satisfy this
group. And if you did have any of those
goals, did you accomplish them? Yeah, I
mean I think I think really the the the
main goal of of any draft is just to
improve the talent level and this is the
biggest um roster building time of the
year. These three days, you know, that's
um you know how many players you're
going to be able to add and um there's
no better no bigger time that you get to
add this volume of players. And so, you
know, I think we go in um, you know,
having feel for our roster, having a
feel for what it looks like, but in the
end, all we want to do is add talent,
add competition, and just improve the
the construction of our roster overall.
>> Mont, you've said throughout the
offseason that you want to kind of build
the foundation for this team, but you
also want to build a team that can
compete [clears throat] in 2026. Where
do you kind of feel like you're at um,
you know, now that the primary roster
building windows of the offseason are
done?
>> Uh, yeah. I mean, I' like I I' I'd say
the roster building never really ends.
You know, it's a it's a constant
evolving. Um, you know, we won't get
into too much competition this spring.
There really is no competition, I should
say. Um, that the real competition won't
start. But, I mean, there's going to be
players that come available next week
that um, you know, because of the draft,
because of free or undrafted free agent
signing, there's going to be another
round of PE guys that are come
available. So, um, you know, where we're
at, I you know, I don't know. We'll see.
our team hasn't been together. We
haven't practiced one time. Um, you
know, we like the players that we've
added in free agency. We like the
players that we've added in the draft.
We think they're going to me mesh well
with um the the core group that we have
here. Um, but we got to get on the
grass. We we we got to get on the grass
and we got to get a lot of new learning
with uh new coaches and and get our team
together. Um, you know, and I know our
guys will be ready to do that.
>> You feel like the roster is in a better
place than it was last season?
>> I do. Yeah.
I'm curious what area was like
specifically
>> uh because we've added good players in
free agency and we added good players in
the draft.
>> Uh last year Kas was one of the most
prolific defenders in the in the
trenches and so as you start to get
through the next phases of the
offseason. What have your conversations
with him been about maybe playing in
season 19 and if so if this is a place
he's considering?
>> Yeah, we've uh you know we've been in
contact with Quas and we're kind of just
in a wait and see mode. You know, we'll
see. um uh he certainly uh earned that
right and uh really enjoyed our year
last year with him and so you know we'll
see what that leads to down the road.
>> Is it hard to for you to look at what on
paper what you have
>> and judge it in terms of and then
against what you see on the field like
have you learned to not do that? Does
that that make sense? Like right now
right now you're looking at your roster
and you're like oh this is a good team
but you don't really know how good it is
until you get on the field. Is that
something you learned throughout your
career not to do? Is that something you
did early to still do it or what?
>> I mean, I would say, you know, 31 other
teams are probably looking at their team
right now and saying they've gotten
better and and have improved. Um, and in
all reality, none of us know, you know,
none of us know until we get out on the
field in September. Um, and how, you
know, how we mesh, how we perform, um,
if we stay healthy, like all those
things. So, um, you know, I think
everybody can say the same, but until
you're out there competing and and when
things mean something, you don't really
know.
>> Gentlemen, thank you.
>> Awesome. Thank you guys.